[
    {
        "question": "Identify the language which is used in data science?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) Ruby is used in data science.",
        "options": [
            "C++",
            "R",
            "Java",
            "Ruby"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct components of data science.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) All of the options are components of data science.",
        "options": [
            "domain expertise",
            "data engineering",
            "advanced computing",
            "all of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a part of the data science process?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Communication building is not a part of the data science process.",
        "options": [
            "communication building",
            "operationalize",
            "model planning",
            "Discovery"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total groups in which data can be characterized is?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Data can be categorized into two groups:  structured and unstructured data.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose whether the following statement is true or false:  Unstructured data is not organized",
        "answer": "Answer: A) True. Unstructured data is not organized.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False",
            "maybe true or false",
            "cannot be determined"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "A column is a  _________- representation of data.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) A column is a vertical representation of data.",
        "options": [
            "Diagonal",
            "Vertical",
            "Top",
            "horizontal"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Among the following identify the one in which dimensionality reduction reduces.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) Dimensionality reduction reduces collinearity.",
        "options": [
            "Performance",
            "Entropy",
            "Stochastics",
            "collinearity"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Machine learning is a subset of which of the following.",
        "answer": "Answer: A) machine learning is a subset of artificial intelligence",
        "options": [
            "Artificial intelligence",
            "deep learning",
            "data learning",
            "none of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "FIND-S algorithm ignores?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) FIND-S algorithm ignores negative",
        "options": [
            "Positive",
            "Negative",
            "Both",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Full form of PAC is _________________",
        "answer": "Answer: B) PAC stands for Probably Approximate Correct.",
        "options": [
            "Probably Approx Cost",
            "Probably Approximate Correct",
            "Probability Approx Communication",
            "Probably Approximate Computation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total types of layer in radial basis function neural networks is ______",
        "answer": "Answer: C) There is a total of 3 Types of layered in radial basis function neural networks.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Procedural Domain Knowledge in a rule-based system, is in the form of?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Explanation: Procedural Domain Knowledge in a rule-based system, is in the form of Production Rules.",
        "options": [
            "Meta-Rules",
            "Control Rules",
            "Production Rules",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following architecture is also known as systolic arrays?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Explanation: MISD architecture is also known as systolic arrays",
        "options": [
            "MISD",
            "SISD",
            "SIMD",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Machines running LISP are also called?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Explanation: Machines running LISP are also called AI workstations",
        "options": [
            "AI Workstations",
            "Time-Sharing Terminals",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "A hybrid Bayesian Network consists of?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Explanation: Discrete and Continuous variables both act as numerical inputs to a hybrid Bayesian network.",
        "options": [
            "Discrete Variables",
            "Continuous Variables",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the key data science skills among the following",
        "answer": "Answer: D) All of the above are the key data science skills.",
        "options": [
            "data visualization",
            "machine learning",
            "Statistics",
            "all of the above"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Identify the revision control system on the following.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Git  is the revision control system",
        "options": [
            "Scipy",
            "Numpy",
            "Git",
            "Slidify"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following options identify the one which is false regarding regression.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) option d is incorrect among the following.",
        "options": [
            "it is used for the prediction",
            "it is used for  interpretation",
            "it relates inputs to outputs",
            "it discovers casual relationships"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the general limitations of the backpropagation rule among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) All of the above general limitations of the backpropagation rule.",
        "options": [
            "slow convergence",
            "Scaling",
            "local minima problem",
            "All  of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the instance-based learner.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Lazy learner is an instance-based learner.",
        "options": [
            "Eager learner",
            "lazy learner",
            "both a and b are correct",
            "none of the above"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "What does K stand for in K mean algorithm?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) K stands for a number of iterations in the K mean algorithm",
        "options": [
            "number of clusters",
            "number of data",
            "number of attributes",
            "Number of iterations"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following machine learning algorithm is based upon the idea of bagging?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Random forest is based on the idea of bagging",
        "options": [
            "decision tree",
            "random-forest",
            "Classification",
            "regression"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose a disadvantage of decision trees among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Decision trees are prone to overfitting",
        "options": [
            "Decision trees are robust to outliers",
            "factor analysis",
            "decision trees are prone to overfit",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a supervised learning",
        "answer": "Answer: A) PCA Is not supervised learning.",
        "options": [
            "PCA",
            "Naive Bayesian",
            "linear regression",
            "Decision tree"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the clustering method which takes care of variance in data",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Gaussian mixture model takes care of variance in data",
        "options": [
            "Decision tree",
            "Gaussian mixture model",
            "K means",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following options choose which one of the following focuses on the discovery of unknown properties on the data.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Data mining focuses on the discovery of unknown properties on the data.",
        "options": [
            "Big data",
            "Data mining",
            "Machine learning",
            "Data wrangling"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the model which is  usually a gold standard for data analysis",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Casual is usually a gold standard for data analysis.",
        "options": [
            "Casual",
            "Inferential",
            "Descriptive",
            "all of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Another name of data fishing is?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Data processing is also known as data dredging.",
        "options": [
            "Data merging",
            "Data dredging",
            "Data bagging",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "CLI stands for ___________",
        "answer": "Answer: A) CLI stands for Command-line interface.",
        "options": [
            "Command-line interface",
            "Command language interface",
            "Command-line intercom",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    null,
    {
        "question": "Among the following, choose the correct application of data science in Healthcare.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) All of the above are applications of data science in Healthcare.",
        "options": [
            "Data science for genomics",
            "Data science for medical imaging",
            "Drug discovery with data science",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the Incorrect CLI command.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) delete is not a CLI command.",
        "options": [
            "clear",
            "rm",
            "delete",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total principles of analytical graphs that exist are __________",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Total principles of analytical graphs that exist are 6.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "4",
            "6",
            "8"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Knowledge in AI can be represented as?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) The representation of knowledge in AI can be done both as Predicate and Propositional Logic",
        "options": [
            "Predicate Logic",
            "Propositional Logic",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Inference engines work on the principle of?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) The modes on which inference engines work are forward and backward chaining",
        "options": [
            "Backward Chaining",
            "Forward Chaining",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Components of an expert system are?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) All the above options comprise the components of an expert system.",
        "options": [
            "Knowledge base",
            "User interface",
            "Inference engine",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many types of observing environments are there?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) There are 2 types of observing environments: Fully and Partial.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "0",
            "1"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Another name of data dredging is",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Data dredging is also known as data snooping",
        "options": [
            "Data booting",
            "Data bagging",
            "Data snooping",
            "Data merging"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Out of the given options, which of the following algorithms uses the least memory?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) DFS uses a lesser amount of memory because at a time the path from the node to a root is only stored in the memory stack, unlike BFS which will have to store the whole tree within it.",
        "options": [
            "DFS",
            "BFS",
            "Both A and B are the same",
            "Cannot be compared"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What are different machine learning methods?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) The machine learning methods include Memorization, Analogy, and Deduction.",
        "options": [
            "Memorization",
            "Analogy",
            "Deduction",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The different types of machine learning are?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) The 3 types of machine learning are: Supervised, Unsupervised, and Reinforcement Learning",
        "options": [
            "Supervised",
            "Unsupervised",
            "Reinforcement",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Artificial Intelligence is associated with computers of which generation?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Fifth Generation computers are said to be able to have Artificial Intelligence within them",
        "options": [
            "Second",
            "First",
            "Fifth",
            "Third"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "PEAS is an abbreviation for?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) PEAS is an abbreviation for Performance, Environment, Actuators, Sensors.",
        "options": [
            "Peace, Environment, Action, Sense",
            "Peer, Environment, Actuators, Sensors",
            "Performance, Environment, Actuators, Sensors",
            "Performance, Environment, Actuators, Sense"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following SGD  variant, which of the following is based on both Momentum and adaptive learning.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Adam, is a deep learning Optimizer that is based on both Momentum and additive learning.",
        "options": [
            "RMSprop",
            "Adam",
            "Nesterov",
            "Adagrad"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the activation function output which is zero centered",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Hyperbolic Tangent activation function is zero centered",
        "options": [
            "Hyperbolic tangent",
            "Rectified linear unit",
            "Sigmoid",
            "Softmax"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following logic function, which of the following cannot be implemented by a  perceptron having two inputs",
        "answer": "Answer: A) XOR cannot be implemented by a  perceptron having two inputs.",
        "options": [
            "XOR",
            "NOR",
            "OR",
            "AND"
        ]
    }
]